MATTHEW HOWARD

Saint Charles, MO 63301

Phone: (314) 624-5710 | Email: mahoward2s@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u>: linkedin.co/in/matthew-h-974498108 | <u>GitHub</u>: github.com/mahoward2s | <u>Portfolio</u>: mahoward2s.github.io/Matt-Howard

SUMMARY

Highly driven and creative Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Biology and Science Education and a passion for Art. Recently earned a certificate in full-stack development from Washington University-St. Louis, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. Effective at utilizing skills and experience to problem solve and create user appealing applications. Reputation for learning quickly and using detail orientation and 'out of the box' thinking to attack and resolve complex problems and projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, React.js, WordPress, Python, C#.

Computer Skills: MS Office, Google Drive, spreadsheets, email, PowerPoint, databases, web

Social Media: Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram, Customer Interaction

Troubleshooting: Assessment, system knowledge, analytical skills, testing, calm mindset,

problem-solving, logic, critical thinking skills, collaboration, communication

Planning: Analysis, conceptual skills, brainstorming, decision-making, forecasting,

problem-solving skills, cost-assessment, requirements-gathering

Project Management Skills: Task management, prioritization, delegation, task separation, scheduling, risk management, Scrum

PROJECTS

Brew Crew | https://brew-crew-kamms.herokuapp.com/login

- Application that provides search results for breweries based on a user's city or state input.
- Responsibilities were the BackEnd, API calls/routes on the FrontEnd, and search bar
- MongoDB, Express, React.Js, Node.Js, Bootstrap, OpenGraph, Bcrypt, Passport, OpenBrewery
- Repository: github.com/Msas12/brew-crew

Covid Is No Joke | https://mahoward2s.github.io/Covid-Is-No-Joke/

- An application that allows users to search states for updated Covid information and provides a Joke of the Day to customers to lighten the mood and provide return visits.
- Responsibility was split between the three of us.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Moment, APIs
- Repository: github.com/mahoward2s/Covid-Is-No-Joke

Adopt Don't Shop | https://project2msksmh.herokuapp.com/

- Application that will guiz the user to view and adopt dogs. Admin can upload dogs.
- Responsibility on the application were incorporating Multer, MySQL, and Handlebars
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Multer, Express, Handlebars, Bcrypt, Passport, Sequelize
- Repository: github.com/Msas12/Project-2

EXPERIENCE

Quality Analyst 2020 – 2021 Auto Assure Ofallon, MO

Use critical thinking to analyze and consolidate reports, metrics, problem analysis, and data analytics. Effectively communicate with management and directors to provide training and growth opportunities.

Key Accomplishments:

- Created 8 Protocols/Procedures for my position/department.
- Trained 9 team members

Concierge
St. Louis Blues/Enterprise Center

2019 - 2020

St. Louis, MO

Effectively communicated with Guest and Management to ensure safety and satisfaction. Problem solved any situation or task that presented itself.

Certified Teacher 2017 – 2019 **FHSD** St. Charles, MO

Divulged lesson plans and instructions to 8 different classes. Demonstrated, educated, and coached on proper techniques, theories, and laboratory testing through multiple modalities. Managed time and organization for test, classroom control, and multiple disciplines. *Key Accomplishments:*

Nominated for Teacher of the Month

Gym Manager/Head Coach CrossFit Xtra Mile-Central

2016 - 2017

St. Louis, MO

Generated different marketing strategies to grow the gym. Utilized graphic design and PhotoShop to create t-shirts and marketing handouts. Maintained athlete records and gym equipment. Managed schedules for 5 coaches and 200 athletes. Created a fun and positive work environment for athletes and coaches.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Washington University, St. Louis, MO

A 6 month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

MA in Science Education: Lindenwood University, St. Charles, MO

BS in Biology/Biomedical Science: Southeast Missouri State University, Cape Girardeau, MO